now if you're sitting there in the pits
of fourth and somebody comes to you and
says the phrase
unconditional love quite often the way
that you imagine that
is kind of like unlimited money
you think of it as oh i can do anything
and still have
approval something like that you don't
actually know what love even vaguely
means and therefore
unconditional love you haven't got a
clue what it actually means
now if you think about it in the context
of just good parenting so every parent
should give their child
unconditional love i'm going to say that
absolutely categorically
right there if there's anything in the
world that i believe with experience it
is that
now that does not mean that every parent
should indulge their child by giving
them their
approval certainly doesn't mean that
every parent should give their child
unconditional candy
right right candy and love are not the
same thing right there's still
boundaries right unconditional love is a
crucible more than it is anything else
right unconditional love is that i make
a commitment
to so fully love you that i
seek in all ways through that love to
support you
in becoming the highest version of
yourself and i am in partnership with
your soul
and your soul is not kind now your soul
knows that to grow you have to go
through
there's an undergoing in growth and to
unconditional love is to be
fully in relationship with your soul's
calling
for you to grow into becoming who it is
you are to become on this earth
which may actually have a great deal of
suffering involved right
right if i see a man on the street i
actually remember this and i'll
um sort of out myself a little bit i was
in i was in an ayahuasca ceremony
and the the question the increase that i
put to myself was the question of what
is
what is mine to do and as it turns out
in in the ceremony there was a young man
probably in his early 20s
who had been able to get his father his
grandmother and his aunt but not his
mother i don't know what happened there
to join them and they were they were
definitely not the kind of folks you'd
expect to be in this kind of a scenario
and dad was sitting next to me and dad
had a very tough time
my dad was undergoing some serious
suffering probably under and
i think he may have been a vietnam
veteran so he was going to some
world-class
suffering and part of me wanted to reach
out to him
and i was feeling his suffering and i
was feeling a oh my gosh
and then all of a sudden it just came
clear to me of oh this is my lesson
my lesson is to actually love him
unconditionally which does not mean to
carry his cross for him
quite the opposite is to actually figure
out with as much discernment as i can
muster which may
not be much right now um
precisely what his mind to do in
relationship to him and precisely what
it is to do in relationship to himself
and there are that's parenting again
right parenting as a child
your job as a parent is not to lift your
child's burden and your
job is not to put on your child of
burdensome medicines to carry
is to support them in growing in their
own capacity to discover for themselves
to build in themselves in increasing
capacity to notice
what is theirs to do and how to actually
hold the cross that is theirs to hold
for the whole and for themselves to grow
into who it is there they become
it is an infinitely challenging task and
you will always get it wrong
that is it though that's the whole story
that's the beginning of the end and i
would just call that friendship by the
way once you recognize that every
relationship is that relationship
and every relationship where you either
try to lift or to impose a burden into
somebody else's
is a sin is an error of the of the most
grievous sort
and that your own your own journey is a
journey that gives you more capacity to
learn
how to under how to discern that then i
just start to get to deep stuff
well that's what peter was trying to do
with jesus he's like don't die at a
cross
i'll stop you i'll save you i'll protect
you and he's like you don't know what
you're talking about
you know you're still operating
i got bad news for you um you're
actually trying to do is you're actually
trying to put down your own burden
which is the burden of witnessing me on
the cross
right right he's mindful the fact you're
actually trying to avoid your own cross
by pretending to carry mine